dondengaeshi detatokoshoubu nerau wa ittou shou
An unexpected ending, deal with it as it comes,
we're aiming for first place
i can feel it donna toki datte hikari o shinjiteru
I Can Feel it, no matter what, I believe in the light
nigirishime ta yume ga koboreochi sou na
When the dream I've attained is
toki ni kagitte omoidasu no
about to fall apart, I remember
aitsu no ano yasashii kao
His kind expression,
mune no oku ga mata tsuyoku nareru no
the core of my heart is strengthened once again
bukkirabou no kokoro ni fire
My blunt mind is set ablaze,
gutto kuru ashita o tsukami tain da
I want to grasp tomorrow as it comes at me
mada mi nu sekai wa kowaku nai
I'm not afraid of the world I haven't seen,
shinji ta mirai desho hora let’s try!
isn't this the future we believed in? Come on Let's try!
kazoekire nai ano namida wa sou sa niji ni kawaru darou
Those countless tears, will they change into a rainbow?
osaekire nai kanashimi mo
That sorrow I can't contain
itsuka wa dakishime rareru ka na
Will I be able to embrace you someday?
yawa na haato ga uzukidashi tara
When my feeble heart begins to throb
arittake asu ni kisu shite ageyou
I give all of my kisses to tomorrow
furue ta mama no chiisana kobushi o tsuyoku mata nigitte
Still trembling, I clench my tiny fist tightly
dondengaeshi detatokoshoubu nerau wa ittou shou
An unexpected ending, deal with it as it comes,
we're aiming for first place
i can feel it donna toki datte hikari o shinjiteru
I Can Feel it, no matter what, I believe in the light
You'll Be My Backup
((カカシ : クッ… リン 逃げろ。
(リン)でも…。
Rin, get out of here!
But...!
足手まといだ。
You're going to get in my way!
土遁！
Earth Style!
土流壁！
Mud Wall!
(バブ)チッ 逃げたか。
Damn, they got away!
(バブ)うわっ！
(イナギ)土遁の中から…。
Wha—?!
From inside the Earth Style?!
リン。
すぐに治療します。
Rin!
I'll start treatment immediately!
(ミナト)どうした カカシ。
What happened, Kakashi?!
ミナト先生 オビト…。
Minato Sensei!
Obito...
(オビト)えっ カカシ リン…。
なんで俺こんなとこに…。
Kakashi? Rin?
What am I doing here?
説明はあと。 それより カカシ
これは どういうことだ？
I'll explain later.
First, Kakashi...
What happened here?
ここまで護衛の者たちと
たどり着いたのですが→
We escorted them safely to this point,
２人が裏切って…。
but the other two were traitors...
Two of them?
２人？
(イワト)頼む…。
Please, I'm not going to make it.
俺は もう助からない。
密書の中身を…。
The contents of the secret missive...
しかし
我々が中身を見ることは…。
But we can't look at its contents...
かまわない。
本物であるか 確認してくれ。
Don't worry about it.
Please, just confirm that
it's the real one.
これは どういうことです？
What does this mean?
私の上官に 私か
同じ班の誰かもう１人に→
My superior told me that
another teammate and I would
both be handed secret missives.
密書を渡すと言われていた…。
そのどちらかが本物であると。
どうして…。
And only one of them would
be the real one.
Why?!
仲間に裏切り者がいるかも
しれないという→
There was intel that there could be
a traitor among us.
情報があったからだ。
じゃあ 本物の密書は？
So who has the real missive?
If the traitor had it,
he wouldn't have attacked me.
裏切り者が持っていれば
私を襲うはずはない ならば…。
So...
彼か…。
カカシ もう１人は…。
It was him.
Kakashi, where's the other guy?
それが 途中で…。
Well, on our way here...
頼む 必ず密書を…。
Please, you must get
the secret missive!
ダメです。
There's nothing I can do.
しまった 聞かれていたか。
Damn it, did they hear us?
カカシ お前 まさか
もう１人を見捨てたのか？
Kakashi.
You didn't leave someone
to die, did you?
俺は 任務を優先させただけだ。
I only prioritized the mission.
掟に従ったまでだ。
掟…。
I followed the rules.
The rules?
掟を守らないヤツは クズだ。
Those who don't follow
the rules are scum.
だけど その結果がこれかよ。
But look at the result!
If you hadn't turned your back
on your comrade,
お前が 仲間を見捨てなきゃ
こんなことになってねえ！
this wouldn't have happened!
Stop, Obito!
やめるんだ オビト。
これは 想定外の出来事だ。
This was an unexpected incident.
カカシのせいじゃない。
Kakashi is not to blame.
Damn it!
クソッ！ 俺は行くぜ。
I'm going!
(カカシ)どこに行く気だ？
(オビト)決まってんだろ！
Go where?
Isn't it obvious?!
ソイツを 助けにだよ。
I'm going to save that guy!
But he's right in
the unexpected incident.
だが 彼は
もう敵の真っただ中だ。
He's right. It's too dangerous.
そのとおりだ 危険すぎる。
初陣で
任務失敗なんて やなこった。
I'm not about to fail
my first mission!
失敗ではない。
これは想定外のことだ。
We didn't fail.
This was an unforeseen occurrence!
カカシ お前 優等生のくせに
頭の回転が悪いな。
Kakashi, for an honor student,
you're pretty dumb.
なに！
よく考えろ。
What did you say?
Think about it.
俺たちが護衛してた４人が
全員消えたんだ。
The four guys we were supposed
to guard have all disappeared.
誰が 俺たちに
想定外のことが起きたって→
Who's gonna support our claim
that this was all unexpected?
証明してくれるんだよ？
もともと
裏切り者がいたってことを→
If the village who requested
this mission
pretends to not have known
about the traitors...
依頼してきた里に
シラを切られたら→
責任を負うのは ミナト先生だ。
Minato Sensei will be forced
to take responsibility!
俺のことは どうでもいい。
任務は終わったんだ オビト。
Never mind me.
Our mission is over, Obito.
言っときますけど→
All I want to say is...
先生が俺をぶん殴って
里に連れ戻そうが→
Sensei, you can keep dragging me
back to the village,
何度だって
置いてきぼりにされたヤツを→
but I won't give up searching
for the guy.
探しにいきますよ。
俺は 仲間を見捨てない。
I never turn my back
on a comrade!
(ミナト/リン)オビト！
– Obito!
ったく…。
Damn it.
止めてもムダのようだね。
I guess it's useless to try
and stop you.
では俺は 彼が落ちた場所。
Then I'll go back to where he fell.
その下流を カカシ。
更に下流を オビトだ。
Kakashi, you check downstream.
And Obito, check beyond that.
リンは カカシについてゆけ。
はい！
Rin, you go with Kakashi.
Right!
いいかい？ 彼を見つけたら
すぐに俺に報告するんだ。
Listen up. Report to me
the minute you find him.
(シンブ)ぐっ…。
あっ… ハァ ハァ ハァ ハァ…。
いたぞ！
He's here!
見つけたぞ。
We found him.
火遁 豪火球の術！
Fire Style! Fireball Jutsu!
チッ…。
There are too many enemies.
《敵が多すぎる》
雷遁 千鳥！
Lighting Style! Chidori!
ぐあ～！
Are you all right?!
大丈夫ですか？
リン 彼を！
Rin! Take care of him!
わかった！ 逃げます。
Got it!
Let's get away from here.
Wait!
待ってくれ。 巻物が…。
The scroll!
引きあげる！
Withdraw!
くっ… オビト リン！ 彼を守れ。
Obito! Rin!
Guard him!
カカシ！ お前は!?
巻物を奪い返す。
What about you, Kakashi?!
I'm getting the scroll back!
無茶だ。 あの数だぞ。
That's reckless!
You saw how many there were!
文句は 言わせない。
彼を救ったのが お前の流儀なら→
I won't let you complain!
If saving him is your Ninja Way,
completing the mission is mine.
任務を遂行するのが 俺の流儀だ。
(オビト)カカシ！
(リン)オビト ミナト先生に連絡を。
Kakashi!
Obito, we have to contact
Minato Sensei!
ああ。
Yeah!
オビト…。
Obito!
(イナギ)キサマ １人で
俺たちの相手をするつもりか。
You bastard, do think you can
take us all on by yourself?
任務は やり遂げる。
I will complete my mission.
やれ。
Kill him.
(ミナト)オビト 見つけたのか？
Obito! Did you find him?
カカシが巻物を追って 敵の中に！
カカシが…。
Kakashi went after the enemy
to get the scroll back!
Kakashi did what?
間に合ってくれ。
I hope I make it in time!
(イナギ)フン！ 来い。
Come on!
ぐあっ… ソイツを逃がすな！
Don't let him... get away!
(ミナト)螺旋閃光 超輪舞吼参式！
Rasen-Flash Super-Circle
Dance Howl Stage Three!
ミナト先生。
Minato Sensei.
これで やりとおせたかな？
キミの信じる流儀は。
So, were you able to uphold
the principles you believe in?
(ミナト)これで
無事に任務は 完了ですね。
This completes the mission.
ええ ありがとう。
私の命を救ってくれて。
Yes...
Thank you for saving my life.
木ノ葉の黄色い閃光。
また どこかで。
The Yellow Flash of the Leaf...
I hope we meet again someday.
では これで。 行こう みんな。
All right then, let's go everyone.
先生 本当の任務って
大変なんですね。
Sensei, missions are
really difficult, aren't they?
そうだね。 頭の中で描いたように
きれいにはいかない。
You're right.
Things don't always go
the way you envision them.
でも 密書が
無事に届けられてよかった。
But I'm glad the secret missive
was delivered safely.
ああ…。
Yes...
とにかく 任務は 達成できたな。
So we successfully
completed the mission.
おそらくな。
Probably.
おそらく？ 何 言ってんだ？
"Probably"? What do you mean?
彼は あのとき…。
Back there, he said...
((ありがとう。
私の命を救ってくれて))
Thank you for saving my life.
任務が達成できていたなら→
If the mission was successful,
自分の命より
密書のことを口にしたと思う。
he would be more concerned
about the secret missive
and not his life.
それって どういうことだよ。
What do you mean?!
彼の持っていた密書も白紙だ。
The missive he had
was also a fake.
は？
きっと俺たちは→
We were probably decoys.
陽動に使われたんだ。
Another team delivered
the real missive.
本物は 別の部隊が
運んだんだろう。
それが Ｃランクの任務に
ミナト先生を指名してきた→
That's the real reason
they requested Minato Sensei
for a C-rank mission.
本当の理由だ。
With Minato Sensei as the escort,
ミナト先生ほどの忍が護衛につけば→
俺たちが いかにも
本物を運んでいるように見える。
it would seem that we were
really guarding the real thing.
お前 いつから そのことに？
When did you figure that out?
最初の巻物がニセモノだったとき
その可能性は考えていた。
I thought it was a possibility
when we discovered
the first missive was a fake.
それじゃ お前 ニセモノかもしれない
巻物を命がけで…。
And you risked your life
to go after a missive
that could have been a fake?
それが任務だ。
That was the mission.
That's my Ninja Way.
(それが 俺の流儀だ))
(オビト)俺は お前のことを
少しは理解していると思っていた。
I thought I understood
a little about you.
But I didn't understand a thing...
だが 俺は
何もわかっちゃいなかった。
それを知ったのは
お前との最後の任務だった。
I finally understood...
on our last mission together.
((カカシは 木ノ葉の白い牙と
恐れられた 天才忍者→
Kakashi is the son of
the genius Ninja, Sakumo Hatake,
feared as the "White Fang"
of the Leaf.
はたけサクモさんの息子でね。
白い牙？
The White Fang?
それじゃ あのときの人が…。
Then that incident?
But...
でも カカシのヤツ
ひと言もそんなこと…。
Kakashi's never said
a word about him.
里の誰もが もちろん カカシも
尊敬する すばらしい人だった。
He was a great man...
Someone respected by everyone
in the village,
and naturally, by Kakashi himself.
あの事件が起きるまでは…。
That is, until that incident...
事件？
Incident?
こんなことを勝手に話しちゃ
いけないのかもしれないけど→
Perhaps, I shouldn't be telling you
something like this...
カカシと同じ班のキミには
知っておいてほしいんだ。
But since you're on
the same team as Kakashi,
I want you to know.
何があったの？
What happened?
Kakashi's father, Sakumo,
took his own life after being slandered.
カカシの父 サクモさんは→
中傷されて ご自分で
自分の命を絶たれたんだ。
５年前 ある極秘任務で→
Five years ago,
he was the leader of a top-secret mission
to infiltrate enemy territory.
隊長として 敵地に潜入した彼は→
He was forced to make a choice.
そこで二択を迫られた。
任務遂行か 仲間の命か。
To execute the mission
or save his comrades' lives...
もちろん 里の掟に従えば
任務放棄はご法度。
Of course, according to
the rules of the village,
completing the mission
was the right thing to do.
However, in order to save
the lives of his comrades,
だが 彼は 仲間の命を救うため
任務を中断したんだ。
he suspended the mission.
That resulted in grave losses
to the Land of Fire and the village,
しかし そのことで
大きな損失を出した火の国や→
and he was blamed for it.
里の仲間は彼を責めた。
あげくの果てには
助けた仲間たちでさえ→
What's more, the very comrades
he saved also criticized him.
彼を中傷したんだ。
The whole ordeal took its toll on
Sakumo, both physically and mentally.
それがもとで 心も体も悪くした
サクモさんは 自ら…。
And finally, he took his own life.
カカシは それ以来 親父さんのことを
口にしなくなり→
From then on, Kakashi never uttered
a word about his father,
and he strictly began to adhere
to every rule and regulation.
掟やルールを守ることに
固執し始めた。
Obito... Try to understand,
even if it's just a little.
(ミナト)オビト 少しでもいい。
わかってあげてね。
カカシにも
悪気があるわけじゃないんだ。
Kakashi means well.
Fire Style: Fireball Jutsu!
《火遁 豪火球の術！》
(リン)キャ～ッ！
(タイセキ)コイツは預からせてもらう。
We're taking this one.
Wait!
待て！
(オビト)チクショウ！
オビト！
Damn it!
Obito, don't go after them!
ヤツらを追うな！
(オビト)何だと!?
What did you say?
２人で このまま任務を続行する。
The two of us will continue
this mission.
Do you realize what you just said?!
お前 今 何言ってんのか
自分で わかってんのか!?
Yeah...
ああ。
忍なら 仲間を犠牲にしてでも
任務の遂行が絶対だ。
A shinobi must sacrifice a comrade
if the mission is at stake.
それが 掟だ。
That's the rule.
お前 そんなもんのために
今まで生死をともにしてきた→
You're willing to simply abandon
a comrade
who's been through
life and death with you,
仲間を簡単に
切り捨てられるっていうのか!?
for something like that?!
お前は何も わかっちゃいない！
You don't understand anything...
掟を破ったヤツが どうなるか。
about what happens to people
who break the rules.
(オビト)俺は 白い牙を
本当の英雄だと思ってる。
I believe the White Fang
was a true hero.
確かに 忍の世界で→
It's true. In the Shinobi World,
someone who breaks the rules
and regulations is regarded as scum...
ルールや掟を破るヤツは
クズ呼ばわりされる。
But...
けどな 仲間を大切にしないヤツは→
those who abandon their comrades
are worse than scum!
それ以上のクズだ！
《オビト : 見つけたぞ》
I found them...
(オビト)カカシ お前 どうして…。
Kakashi... Why are you—?!
白銀の髪に その白光のチャクラ刀。
That silver-white hair and
White Chakra Blade!
まさか お前 木ノ葉の白い牙!?
Don't tell me you're...
the "White Fang" of the Leaf?!
これは 父の形見だ。
This is a memento of my father's.
なるほどな 白い牙のガキか。
なら ビビる必要はねえな。
I see. You're the White Fang's kid.
Then there's no need
to be afraid of you.
(オビト)どこだ？
Where is he?
Obito, behind you!
オビト！ 後ろだ!!
ぐあっ！ 眼が…。
My eye!
(オビト)カカシ!!
Kakashi!
うっ…。
忍が泣くなっての。
A shinobi shouldn't cry...
I'm not dead yet.
まだ死んだわけじゃない。
Don't lose focus.
気を抜くなよ。
I'm always just talk...
《オビト : 俺は いつも口先だけで…。
Other people are always saving me...
みんなに助けられてばっかだ。
けど…》
But...
((オビト : 仲間を大切にしないヤツは
それ以上のクズだ))
Those who abandon their comrades
are worse than scum!
《あの言葉だけは
口先だけにしたくはないんだ》
I don't want them
to be empty words.
《タイセキ : 死ね！》
Die!
(タイセキ)な… なぜだ？
見えるわけはない…。
H-How?
There's no way you can see me!
オビト お前…。
Obito... You—!
(な… なんだ？ その眼は…))
W-What is that eye?
今回は 俺が メイン。
お前が バックアップだ カカシ。
This time, I'll take point and
you'll be my backup, Kakashi.
久かたぶりのツーマンセルだな。
しくじるなよ オビト。
It's been a while since
we were a two-man squad.
Don't stumble, Obito.
Are you prepared for this?
覚悟は いいか？
ああ。
Yeah...
最後の作戦が
お前とでよかったよ。
I'm glad my final op will
have been with you.
オビト… カカシ…。
Obito... Kakashi.
(マダラ)オビト お前に預けたものを
すべて返してもらう。
Obito, I'm taking back everything
I loaned you.
Especially that left eye...
特に左目が
まだ入っていなくてな。
気になるか？ マダラ。
Are you worried, Madara?
You told me once that
only with both together
写輪眼は 左右揃って
本来の力を発揮するもの。
could the Sharingan's true power
be unleashed.
そう言ったよな。 なら…。
And so...
You're wrong. Those are Rinnegan,
not just Sharingan.
(マダラ)違う。
もう写輪眼ではない。 輪廻眼だ。
違う。
You're wrong.
(マダラ)うん？
I was talking about these eyes.
こっちのことを言ってるんだよ。
((やっと揃ったね。
We're finally all together!
You're late again!
(カカシ)またまた遅刻だよ！ お前は。
A lot happened on my way here
and I got lost...
(オビト)いや 途中 いろいろあって
道に迷っちゃってさ。
(カカシ)お前の歩く道は
いつも どんだけ→
How come every path
you take is a roundabout route?
曲がりくねってるってのよ ホント。
Just walk a straight line!
まっすぐ来い！
I told you, a lot of stuff happened
along the way!
だから 道すがら いろいろ
あったって言ってんだろうが!!
忍なら決まりを守れ。
お前の その怠慢が→
A shinobi must follow the rules!
Your carelessness could end up
putting your comrades in danger!
仲間を危機に陥れる
可能性だってあんだから。
なら 俺が お前らを守ってやる。
決まりを守るかわりによ。
Then I'll just protect you guys!
Instead of obeying the rules!
Do you know what
you're even saying?!
(カカシ)どの口が言ってんだ。
(オビト)眼は口ほどにものを言う。
Eyes speak louder than words!
Once my Sharingan are awakened,
they won't be silent!
俺の写輪眼が開眼したら
黙ってねえぜ！
はぁ～。
(カカシ)お前の写輪眼なんて→
Your Sharingan won't amount
to anything!
役立つとは思えないし そもそも
開眼してないなら黙っとけ！
Besides, they're not awakened yet,
so shut up!
You shut up!
(オビト)うるせぇ！
マスクで口隠してるくせに→
Obviously, you must talk too much
口が ものを
言いすぎなんだよ お前は！
since you have to keep
your mouth covered with a mask!
テメエこそ黙っとけ！
So you shut up!
They're not falling into line
at all, are they?
(ミナト)なかなか
足並みが揃わないね。
That's for sure.
確かに… でもね 先生。
うん？
But you know, Sensei...
I challenge you, Kakashi!
(ガイ)勝負だ カカシ！
Not you again, Beast Face!
またテメエか 猛獣顔！
来んじゃねえ！
Leave us alone!
How did I end up with
classmates like these?
(まったく
俺の同期どもは…))
《マダラ : ナルトを復活させるためには→
In order to resurrect Naruto,
they need the Rinnegan
and the Nine Tails.
輪廻眼と九尾
これらを持つオビトを→
Obito has them both,
時空間へ
飛ばしさえしなければいい。
so as long as I don't allow him
to teleport away to his time-space...
神威の移動時間より→
And I've already discovered
that my attacks are faster than
their Kamui's transfer speed.
俺の攻撃のほうが速いのは
さっきわかった。
おそらく コイツらは どちらか一方が
俺に陽動をしかけてくる間に→
There's no doubt one of them
will try to distract me
while the other performs the Kamui.
もう一方が 神威をする。
オビト自ら飛ぶか それとも
カカシに飛ばせるかの二択》
Obito will teleport himself or
have Kakashi teleport him.
This time, I'll take point and
you'll be my backup, Kakashi.
((今回は 俺が メイン。
お前が バックアップだ カカシ))
《マダラ : どちらにしろ
二択ともオビトが言ったように→
Whatever they decide,
I'll be able to stop Obito again.
とらえることができる。
手っ取り早く輪墓でいくか…。
I should keep it fast and
simple with Limbo...
No... I shouldn't use that as long as
Obito still has the Rinnegan.
いや オビトに輪廻眼がある以上
それはやるべきではない。
なら２人同時に
攻撃しさえすればいい》
Then I'll attack them
both simultaneously!
But you know, Sensei...
((リン : でもね 先生。
そこは私に任せて。
Let me handle this.
I'll make the two of them—!
私が ２人をちゃんと…。
Let's go... you guys!
(行くよ！ ２人とも！ フフッ！))
(２人)神威！
Kamui!
お互い まったく同時に神威を。
They both released their Kamui
at the same time!
術のスピードを倍にして飛ぶとはな…。
And doubled the speed of the jutsu!
(サクラ)オビト。
大丈夫だ。
Obito!
Don't worry.
俺が ナルトを助けてやる。
I'm here to help Naruto...
信用できるの？
Can I trust you?
俺は 昔から まっすぐ素直には
歩けなくってね。
Ever since I was a kid,
I've never been able to walk
a straight path.
But I've finally gotten to
where I needed to go.
だが やっと… たどり着いた。
You actually had
perfect timing for once.
今回ばかりは
いいときに来てくれたよ。
《カカシを助けてくれて
ありがとう ガイ》
Thanks for saving Kakashi...
Guy!
Are you all right, Kakashi?!
(ガイ)大丈夫か？ カカシ。
I've seen you before.
どこかで見たな。
んっ!? 誰だ？ あれ。
Who is that?
hitori ja nai yo
You're not alone
osoreru mono nante nai kara
There's nothing to be afraid of
ikou saa me o ake te
Let's go, now open your eyes
butsukatte ita
I was crashing into you
hontou wa oitsuki taku te
I just wanted to catch up so badly
kizutsuke atte
We hurt one another
tsunagi tomeru kizuna hoshiku te
I just wanted a bond to connect me to you
"gomen" wasure nai de
"I'm sorry" Don't forget
shinji te matte te
Trust in me and wait
mukae ni ikun da
I'll come for you
yuuki no tomoshibi terashidase yowa sa o
The light of courage, reveal our weaknesses
kizu datte itami datte wakeae ba heiki da
If we share our wounds and pain, we'll be fine
kimi no senaka osu musun da yakusoku
This is the promise I made you push you forward
itsu datte hanare tatte
No matter when, even if we're apart
shinjirareru kizuna wa mune ni nemutteru
The bond I believe in rests in my heart
You maybe reinforcements,
but you're nothing more than pebbles.
＜敗戦ということを知らない
日本が初めて味わった敗戦に→
You won't make any difference
at this point.
That's Madara?
１億 総国民が
虚脱状態に入りました。
Only Senjutsu works against him...
その中に
爽やかに聴こえてきた歌声…＞
and one more thing: physical attacks
such as Taijutsu.
So, it's show time for
the wild blue beast, eh?
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"The Blue Beast vs. Six Paths Madara"
Eight Inner Gates!
Seventh Gate of Shock! Open!